<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elastic on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/tag/elastic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elastic on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 12:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/tag/elastic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Denormalise Data for Analysis in Kibana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/24/using-r-to-denormalise-data-for-analysis-in-kibana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 12:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/24/using-r-to-denormalise-data-for-analysis-in-kibana/</guid>
      <description>Kibana is a tool from Elastic that makes analysis of data held in Elasticsearch really easy and very powerful. Because Elasticsearch has very loose schema that can evolve on demand it makes it very quick to get up and running with some cool visualisations and analysis on any set of data. I demonstrated this in a blog post last year, taking a CSV file and loading it into Elasticsearch via Logstash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling the Data Pipeline with Kafka - A (Very) Simple Real Life Example</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 21:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been playing around with the ELK stack (now officially known as the Elastic stack) collecting data from an IRC channel with Elastic&amp;rsquo;s Logstash, storing it in Elasticsearch and analysing it with Kibana. But, this isn&amp;rsquo;t an &amp;ldquo;ELK&amp;rdquo; post - this is a Kafka post! ELK is just some example data manipulation tooling that helps demonstrate the principles.
As I wrote about last year, Apache Kafka provides a handy way to build flexible &amp;ldquo;pipelines&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>