<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Log4j on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/tag/log4j/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Log4j on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 15:28:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/tag/log4j/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Kafka Connect to log REST HTTP messages to a separate file</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/06/12/configuring-kafka-connect-to-log-rest-http-messages-to-a-separate-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 15:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/06/12/configuring-kafka-connect-to-log-rest-http-messages-to-a-separate-file/</guid>
      <description>Kafka&amp;rsquo;s Connect API is a wondrous way of easily bringing data in and out of Apache Kafka without having to write a line of code. By choosing a Connector from the many available, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to set up and end-to-end data pipeline with just a few lines of configuration. You can configure this by hand, or you can use the Confluent Control Center, for both management and monitoring:
BUT &amp;hellip; there are times when not all goes well - perhaps your source has gone offline, or one of your targets has been misconfigured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect JDBC - Oracle - Number of groups must be positive</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/27/kafka-connect-jdbc-oracle-number-of-groups-must-be-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 15:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/27/kafka-connect-jdbc-oracle-number-of-groups-must-be-positive/</guid>
      <description>There are various reasons for this error, but the one I hit was that the table name is case sensitive, and returned from Oracle by the JDBC driver in uppercase.
If you specify the tablename in your connecter config in lowercase, it won&amp;rsquo;t be matched, and this error is thrown. You can validate this by setting debug logging (edit etc/kafka/connect-log4j.properties to set log4j.rootLogger=DEBUG, stdout), and observe: (I&amp;rsquo;ve truncated some of the output for legibility)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>