<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kafka Connect on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/tag/kafka-connect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kafka Connect on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 22:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/tag/kafka-connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Tips and Tricks with KSQL and Kafka</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/15/docker-tips-and-tricks-with-ksql-and-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 22:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/15/docker-tips-and-tricks-with-ksql-and-kafka/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago a colleague of mine told me about this thing called Docker, and I must admit I dismissed it as a fad…how wrong was I. Docker, and Docker Compose, are one of my key tools of the trade. With them I can build self-contained environments for tutorials, demos, conference talks etc. Tear it down, run it again, without worrying that somewhere a local config changed and will break things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect CLI tricks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/03/kafka-connect-cli-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 14:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/03/kafka-connect-cli-tricks/</guid>
      <description>I do lots of work with Kafka Connect, almost entirely in Distributed mode—even just with 1 node -&amp;gt; makes scaling out much easier when/if needed. Because I&amp;rsquo;m using Distributed mode, I use the Kafka Connect REST API to configure and manage it. Whilst others might use GUI REST tools like Postman etc, I tend to just use the commandline. Here are some useful snippets that I use all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect and Oracle data types</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/05/21/kafka-connect-and-oracle-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/05/21/kafka-connect-and-oracle-data-types/</guid>
      <description>The Kafka Connect JDBC Connector by default does not cope so well with:
 NUMBER columns with no defined precision/scale. You may end up with apparent junk (bytes) in the output, or just errors. TIMESTAMP WITH LOCAL TIME ZONE. Throws JDBC type -102 not currently supported warning in the log.  Read more about NUMBER data type in the Oracle docs.
tl;dr : How do I make it work? There are several options:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Data from MongoDB into Kafka with Kafka Connect and Debezium</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/27/streaming-data-from-mongodb-into-kafka-with-kafka-connect-and-debezium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/27/streaming-data-from-mongodb-into-kafka-with-kafka-connect-and-debezium/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I am not a MongoDB person. These steps may or may not be appropriate and proper. But they worked for me :) Feel free to post in comments if I&amp;rsquo;m doing something wrong
MongoDB config - enabling replica sets For Debezium to be able to stream changes from MongoDB, Mongo needs to have replication configured:
Docs: Replication / Convert a Standalone to a Replica Set
Stop Mongo:
rmoff@proxmox01 ~&amp;gt; sudo service mongod stop  Add replica set config to /etc/mongod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Data from MySQL into Kafka with Kafka Connect and Debezium</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/24/streaming-data-from-mysql-into-kafka-with-kafka-connect-and-debezium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 14:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/24/streaming-data-from-mysql-into-kafka-with-kafka-connect-and-debezium/</guid>
      <description>Debezium is a CDC tool that can stream changes from MySQL, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL into Kafka, using Kafka Connect. In this article we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to set it up and examine the format of the data. A subsequent article will show using this realtime stream of data from a RDBMS and join it to data originating from other sources, using KSQL.
The software versions used here are:
 Confluent Platform 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming data from Kafka into Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/06/streaming-data-from-kafka-into-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 22:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/06/streaming-data-from-kafka-into-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>This article is part of a series exploring Streaming ETL in practice. You can read about setting up the ingest of realtime events from a standard Oracle platform, and building streaming ETL using KSQL.
This post shows how we take data streaming in from an Oracle transactional system into Kafka, and simply stream it onwards into Elasticsearch. This is a common pattern, for enabling rapid search or analytics against data held in systems elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle GoldenGate / Kafka Connect Handler troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/09/12/oracle-goldengate-kafka-connect-handler-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 21:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/09/12/oracle-goldengate-kafka-connect-handler-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>The Replicat was kapput:
GGSCI (localhost.localdomain) 3&amp;gt; info rkconnoe REPLICAT RKCONNOE Last Started 2017-09-12 17:06 Status ABENDED Checkpoint Lag 00:00:00 (updated 00:46:34 ago) Log Read Checkpoint File /u01/app/ogg/dirdat/oe000000 First Record RBA 0  So checking the OGG error log ggserr.log showed
2017-09-12T17:06:17.572-0400 ERROR OGG-15051 Oracle GoldenGate Delivery, rkconnoe.prm: Java or JNI exception: oracle.goldengate.util.GGException: Error detected handling operation added event. 2017-09-12T17:06:17.572-0400 ERROR OGG-01668 Oracle GoldenGate Delivery, rkconnoe.prm: PROCESS ABENDING.  So checking the replicat log dirrpt/RKCONNOE_info_log4j.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect - JsonDeserializer with schemas.enable requires &#34;schema&#34; and &#34;payload&#34; fields</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/09/06/kafka-connect-jsondeserializer-with-schemas.enable-requires-schema-and-payload-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/09/06/kafka-connect-jsondeserializer-with-schemas.enable-requires-schema-and-payload-fields/</guid>
      <description>An error that I see coming up frequently in the Kafka Connect community (e.g. mailing list, Slack group, StackOverflow) is:
JsonDeserializer with schemas.enable requires &amp;quot;schema&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;payload&amp;quot; fields and may not contain additional fields  or
No fields found using key and value schemas for table: foo-bar  You can see an explanation, and solution, for the issue in my StackOverflow answer here: https://stackoverflow.com/a/45940013/350613
If you&amp;rsquo;re using schemas.enable in the Connector configuration, you must have schema and payload as the root-level elements of your JSON message ( Which is pretty much verbatim what the error says 😁), like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Kafka Connect to log REST HTTP messages to a separate file</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/06/12/configuring-kafka-connect-to-log-rest-http-messages-to-a-separate-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 15:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/06/12/configuring-kafka-connect-to-log-rest-http-messages-to-a-separate-file/</guid>
      <description>Kafka&amp;rsquo;s Connect API is a wondrous way of easily bringing data in and out of Apache Kafka without having to write a line of code. By choosing a Connector from the many available, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to set up and end-to-end data pipeline with just a few lines of configuration. You can configure this by hand, or you can use the Confluent Control Center, for both management and monitoring:
BUT &amp;hellip; there are times when not all goes well - perhaps your source has gone offline, or one of your targets has been misconfigured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle GoldenGate -&gt; Kafka Connect - &#34;Failed to serialize Avro data&#34;</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/11/29/oracle-goldengate-kafka-connect-failed-to-serialize-avro-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 22:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/11/29/oracle-goldengate-kafka-connect-failed-to-serialize-avro-data/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Make sure that key.converter.schema.registry.url and value.converter.schema.registry.url are specified, and that there are no trailing whitespaces.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been building on previous work I&amp;rsquo;ve done with Oracle GoldenGate and Kafka Connect, looking at how to have the change records from the Oracle database come through to Kafka in Avro format rather than the default JSON that the sample configuration gives.
Simply changing the Kafka Connect OGG configuration file (confluent.properties) from
value.converter=org.apache.kafka.connect.json.JsonConverter key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect - java.lang.IncompatibleClassChangeError</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/11/24/kafka-connect-java.lang.incompatibleclasschangeerror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/11/24/kafka-connect-java.lang.incompatibleclasschangeerror/</guid>
      <description>I hit this error running Kafka Connect HDFS connector from Confluent Platform v3.1.1 on BigDataLite 4.6:
[oracle@bigdatalite ~]$ connect-standalone /etc/schema-registry/connect-avro-standalone.properties /etc/kafka-connect-hdfs/quickstart-hdfs.properties [...] Exception in thread &amp;quot;main&amp;quot; java.lang.IncompatibleClassChangeError: Implementing class at java.lang.ClassLoader.defineClass1(Native Method) at java.lang.ClassLoader.defineClass(ClassLoader.java:763) at java.security.SecureClassLoader.defineClass(SecureClassLoader.java:142) at java.net.URLClassLoader.defineClass(URLClassLoader.java:467) at java.net.URLClassLoader.access$100(URLClassLoader.java:73) at java.net.URLClassLoader$1.run(URLClassLoader.java:368) at java.net.URLClassLoader$1.run(URLClassLoader.java:362) at java.security.AccessController.doPrivileged(Native Method) at java.net.URLClassLoader.findClass(URLClassLoader.java:361) at java.lang.ClassLoader.loadClass(ClassLoader.java:424) at sun.misc.Launcher$AppClassLoader.loadClass(Launcher.java:331) at java.lang.ClassLoader.loadClass(ClassLoader.java:357) at java.lang.ClassLoader.defineClass1(Native Method) at java.lang.ClassLoader.defineClass(ClassLoader.java:763)  The fix was to unset the CLASSPATH first:
unset CLASSPATH  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect JDBC - Oracle - Number of groups must be positive</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/27/kafka-connect-jdbc-oracle-number-of-groups-must-be-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 15:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/27/kafka-connect-jdbc-oracle-number-of-groups-must-be-positive/</guid>
      <description>There are various reasons for this error, but the one I hit was that the table name is case sensitive, and returned from Oracle by the JDBC driver in uppercase.
If you specify the tablename in your connecter config in lowercase, it won&amp;rsquo;t be matched, and this error is thrown. You can validate this by setting debug logging (edit etc/kafka/connect-log4j.properties to set log4j.rootLogger=DEBUG, stdout), and observe: (I&amp;rsquo;ve truncated some of the output for legibility)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Connect - HDFS with Hive Integration - SchemaProjectorException - Schema version required</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/19/kafka-connect-hdfs-with-hive-integration-schemaprojectorexception-schema-version-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 14:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/07/19/kafka-connect-hdfs-with-hive-integration-schemaprojectorexception-schema-version-required/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some noodling around with Confluent&amp;rsquo;s Kafka Connect recently, as part of gaining a wider understanding into Kafka. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Kafka Connect this page gives a good idea of the thinking behind it.
One issue that I hit defeated my Google-fu so I&amp;rsquo;m recording it here to hopefully help out fellow n00bs.
The pipeline that I&amp;rsquo;d set up looked like this:
 Eneco&amp;rsquo;s Twitter Source streaming tweets to a Kafka topic Confluent&amp;rsquo;s HDFS Sink to stream tweets to HDFS and define Hive table automagically over them  It worked great, but only if I didn&amp;rsquo;t enable the Hive integration part.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>