<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubiquiti on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/categories/ubiquiti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubiquiti on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 11:35:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/categories/ubiquiti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Network Data with Apache Kafka, KSQL, and Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/06/17/analysing-network-data-with-apache-kafka-ksql-and-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 11:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/06/17/analysing-network-data-with-apache-kafka-ksql-and-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>In this article I demonstrated how to use KSQL to filter streams of network event data. As well as filtering, KSQL can be used to easily enrich streams. In this article we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this enriched data can be used to drive analysis in Elasticsearch and Kibana—and how KSQL again came into use for building some stream processing as a result of the discovery made.
The data came from my home Ubiquiti router, and took two forms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning Ubiquiti&#39;s MongoDB instance to a separate server</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/27/cloning-ubiquitis-mongodb-instance-to-a-separate-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/03/27/cloning-ubiquitis-mongodb-instance-to-a-separate-server/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: I am not a MongoDB person (even if it is Web Scale X-D) - below instructions may work for you, they may not. Use with care!
For some work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing I wanted to access the data in Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s Unifi controller which it stores in MongoDB. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to risk my actual Unifi device by changing local settings to enable remote access, and also because the version of MongoDB on it is older than ideal, I wanted to clone the data elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>