<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kibana on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/tag/kibana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kibana on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 16:16:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/tag/kibana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Window Timestamps in KSQL / Integration with Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/09/03/window-timestamps-in-ksql-integration-with-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 16:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/09/03/window-timestamps-in-ksql-integration-with-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>KSQL provides the ability to create windowed aggregations. For example, count the number of messages in a 1 minute window, grouped by a particular column:
CREATE TABLE RATINGS_BY_CLUB_STATUS AS \ SELECT CLUB_STATUS, COUNT(*) AS RATING_COUNT \ FROM RATINGS_WITH_CUSTOMER_DATA \ WINDOW TUMBLING (SIZE 1 MINUTES) \ GROUP BY CLUB_STATUS;  How KSQL, and Kafka Streams, stores the window timestamp associated with an aggregate, has recently changed. See #1497 for details.
Whereas previously the Kafka message timestamp (accessible through the KSQL ROWTIME system column) stored the start of the window for which the aggregate had been calculated, this changed in July 2018 to instead be the timestamp of the latest message to update that aggregate value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kibana Timelion - Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/01/18/kibana-timelion-anomaly-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 19:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2017/01/18/kibana-timelion-anomaly-detection/</guid>
      <description>Using the holt function in Timelion to do anomaly detection on Metricbeat data in Kibana:
Expression:
$thres=0.02, .es(index=&#39;metricbeat*&#39;,metric=&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct&#39;).lines(1).if(eq, 0, null).holt(0.9, 0.1, 0.9, 0.5h).color(#eee).lines(10).label(&#39;Prediction&#39;), .es(index=&#39;metricbeat*&#39;,metric=&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct&#39;).color(#666).lines(1).label(Actual), .es(index=&#39;metricbeat*&#39;,metric=&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct&#39;).lines(1).if(eq, 0, null).holt(0.9, 0.1, 0.9, 0.5h).subtract(.es(index=&#39;metricbeat*&#39;,metric=&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct&#39;)).abs().if(lt, $thres, null, .es(index=&#39;metricbeat*&#39;,metric=&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct&#39;)).points(10,3,0).color(#c66).label(&#39;Anomaly&#39;).title(&#39;max:system.cpu.user.pct / @rmoff&#39;)  References:
 https://twitter.com/rashidkpc/status/762754396111327232 https://github.com/elastic/timelion/issues/87 https://github.com/elastic/timelion/blob/master/FUNCTIONS.md  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kibana Timelion - Series Calculations - Difference from One Week Ago</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/23/kibana-timelion-series-calculations-difference-from-one-week-ago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 09:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/23/kibana-timelion-series-calculations-difference-from-one-week-ago/</guid>
      <description>I wrote recently about Kibana&amp;rsquo;s excellent Timelion feature, which brings time-series visualisations to Kibana. In the comments Ben Huang asked:
 do you know how to show whats the difference between this Friday and last Friday by Timelion?
 So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d answer properly here.
Timelion includes mathematical functions including add and subtract, as well as the ability to show data offset by an amount of time. So to answer Ben&amp;rsquo;s query, we combine the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with Elasticsearch, Kibana, and Timelion</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I wrote about Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with InfluxDB and Grafana, in which InfluxDB provided the data store for the ingest rate data, and Grafana the frontend.
Mark Walkom reminded me on twitter that the next release of Logstash will add more functionality in this area - and that it&amp;rsquo;ll integrate back into the Elastic stack:
@rmoff nice, LS 5.0 will have APIs exposing metrics too. they’ll be integrated back into Marvel/Monitoring!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Denormalise Data for Analysis in Kibana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/24/using-r-to-denormalise-data-for-analysis-in-kibana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 12:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/24/using-r-to-denormalise-data-for-analysis-in-kibana/</guid>
      <description>Kibana is a tool from Elastic that makes analysis of data held in Elasticsearch really easy and very powerful. Because Elasticsearch has very loose schema that can evolve on demand it makes it very quick to get up and running with some cool visualisations and analysis on any set of data. I demonstrated this in a blog post last year, taking a CSV file and loading it into Elasticsearch via Logstash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling the Data Pipeline with Kafka - A (Very) Simple Real Life Example</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 21:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been playing around with the ELK stack (now officially known as the Elastic stack) collecting data from an IRC channel with Elastic&amp;rsquo;s Logstash, storing it in Elasticsearch and analysing it with Kibana. But, this isn&amp;rsquo;t an &amp;ldquo;ELK&amp;rdquo; post - this is a Kafka post! ELK is just some example data manipulation tooling that helps demonstrate the principles.
As I wrote about last year, Apache Kafka provides a handy way to build flexible &amp;ldquo;pipelines&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with Kibana Timelion</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/29/experiments-with-kibana-timelion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/29/experiments-with-kibana-timelion/</guid>
      <description>Timelion was released in November 2015 and with the 4.4.2 release of Kibana is available as a native visualisation once installed. It adds some powerful capabilities to Kibana as an timeseries analysis tool, using its own data manipulation language.
Installing Timelion is a piece of cake:
./bin/kibana plugin -i kibana/timelion  After restarting Kibana, you&amp;rsquo;ll see it as an option from the application picker
There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a learning curve with Timelion, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My latest IRC client : Kibana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/24/my-latest-irc-client-kibana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/24/my-latest-irc-client-kibana/</guid>
      <description>OK, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely true. But my read-only client, certainly.
I was perusing the Logstash input plugins recently when I noticed that there was one for IRC. Being a fan of IRC and a regular on the #obihackers channel, I thought this could be fun and yet another great example of how easy the Elastic stack is to work with.
Installation is a piece of cake:
wget https://download.elasticsearch.org/elasticsearch/release/org/elasticsearch/distribution/zip/elasticsearch/2.2.1/elasticsearch-2.2.1.zip wget https://download.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>