<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presenting on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/categories/presenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presenting on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 12:38:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/categories/presenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So how DO you make those cool diagrams?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/10/so-how-do-you-make-those-cool-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 12:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/10/so-how-do-you-make-those-cool-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>I write and speak lots about Kafka, and get a fair few questions from this. The most common question is actually nothing to do with Kafka, but instead:
 How do you make those cool diagrams?
 So here&amp;rsquo;s a short, and longer, answer!
tl;dr An iOS app called Paper, from a company called FiftyThree
So, how DO you make those cool diagrams? Disclaimer: This is a style that I have copied straight from my esteemed colleagues at Confluent, including Neha Narkhede and Ben Stopford, as well as others including Martin Kleppmann.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax highlighting code for presentation slides</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/06/20/syntax-highlighting-code-for-presentation-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 18:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/06/20/syntax-highlighting-code-for-presentation-slides/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve got a code sample you want to share in a presentation, but whilst it looks beautiful in your text-editor with syntax highlighting, it&amp;rsquo;s fugly in Keynote? You could screenshot it and paste the image into your slide, but you just know that you&amp;rsquo;ll want to change that code, and end up re-snapshotting it…what a PITA.
Better to have a nicely syntax-highlighted code snippet that you can paste as formatted text into Keynote and amend from there as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>