<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logstash on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/tag/logstash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logstash on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:45:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/tag/logstash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with Elasticsearch, Kibana, and Timelion</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I wrote about Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with InfluxDB and Grafana, in which InfluxDB provided the data store for the ingest rate data, and Grafana the frontend.
Mark Walkom reminded me on twitter that the next release of Logstash will add more functionality in this area - and that it&amp;rsquo;ll integrate back into the Elastic stack:
@rmoff nice, LS 5.0 will have APIs exposing metrics too. they’ll be integrated back into Marvel/Monitoring!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with InfluxDB and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/12/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-influxdb-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 20:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/05/12/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-influxdb-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to easily monitor the rate at which Logstash is ingesting data, as well as in future articles the rate at which Elasticsearch is indexing it. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice little touch to add to any project involving Logstash, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do.
Logstash is powerful tool for data ingest, processing, and distribution. It originated as simply the pipe to slurp at log files and put them into Elasticsearch, but has evolved into a whole bunch more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Data through Oracle GoldenGate to Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/14/streaming-data-through-oracle-goldengate-to-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 22:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/14/streaming-data-through-oracle-goldengate-to-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>Recently added to the oracledi project over at java.net is an adaptor enabling Oracle GoldenGate (OGG) to send data to Elasticsearch. This adds a powerful alternative to [micro-]batch extract via JDBC from Oracle to Elasticsearch, which I wrote about recently over at the Elastic blog.
Elasticsearch is a &amp;lsquo;document store&amp;rsquo; widely used for both search and analytics. It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve written a lot about (here and here for archives), as well as spoken about - preaching the good word, as it were, since the Elastic stack as a whole is very very good at what it does and a pleasure to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling the Data Pipeline with Kafka - A (Very) Simple Real Life Example</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 21:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/04/12/decoupling-the-data-pipeline-with-kafka-a-very-simple-real-life-example/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been playing around with the ELK stack (now officially known as the Elastic stack) collecting data from an IRC channel with Elastic&amp;rsquo;s Logstash, storing it in Elasticsearch and analysing it with Kibana. But, this isn&amp;rsquo;t an &amp;ldquo;ELK&amp;rdquo; post - this is a Kafka post! ELK is just some example data manipulation tooling that helps demonstrate the principles.
As I wrote about last year, Apache Kafka provides a handy way to build flexible &amp;ldquo;pipelines&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My latest IRC client : Kibana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/24/my-latest-irc-client-kibana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/24/my-latest-irc-client-kibana/</guid>
      <description>OK, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely true. But my read-only client, certainly.
I was perusing the Logstash input plugins recently when I noticed that there was one for IRC. Being a fan of IRC and a regular on the #obihackers channel, I thought this could be fun and yet another great example of how easy the Elastic stack is to work with.
Installation is a piece of cake:
wget https://download.elasticsearch.org/elasticsearch/release/org/elasticsearch/distribution/zip/elasticsearch/2.2.1/elasticsearch-2.2.1.zip wget https://download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun and Games with Oracle GoldenGate, Kafka, and Logstash on BigDataLite 4.4</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/16/fun-and-games-with-oracle-goldengate-kafka-and-logstash-on-bigdatalite-4.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2016/03/16/fun-and-games-with-oracle-goldengate-kafka-and-logstash-on-bigdatalite-4.4/</guid>
      <description>The Oracle by Example (ObE) here demonstrating how to use Goldengate to replicate transactions big data targets such as HDFS is written for the BigDataLite 4.2.1, and for me didn&amp;rsquo;t work on the current latest version, 4.4.0.
The OBE (and similar Hands On Lab PDF) assume the presence of pmov.prm and pmov.properties in /u01/ogg/dirprm/. On BDL 4.4 there&amp;rsquo;s only the extract to from Oracle configuration, emov.
Fortunately it&amp;rsquo;s still possible to run this setup out of the box in BDL 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>